So now let's talk about Amazon Keyspaces,
Bây giờ hãy nói về Amazon Keyspaces,
and Keyspaces is a managed Apache Cassandra on AWS.
Keyspaces là dịch vụ Cassandra được quản lý trên AWS.
So Cassandra is an open-source NoSQL distributed database,
Cassandra là cơ sở dữ liệu NoSQL phân tán mã nguồn mở,
and so, with Keyspaces,
và với Keyspaces,
you get Cassandra directly managed on the cloud by AWS.
bạn có Cassandra được AWS quản lý trực tiếp trên cloud.
So it's going to be a serverless type of service,
Nó là dịch vụ dạng serverless,
it's scalable, it's highly available,
có thể mở rộng, rất sẵn sàng,
and fully managed by AWS,
và được AWS quản lý hoàn toàn,
and it will automatically scale tables up and down based
tự động scale bảng lên xuống theo
on the application's traffic.
lưu lượng ứng dụng.
The tables' data is going to be replicated three times
Dữ liệu bảng được sao chép ba lần
across multiple AZ,
trên nhiều AZ,
and to perform your queries on top of Keyspaces,
và để query trên Keyspaces,
you are going to use the Cassandra Query Language or CQL.
bạn dùng Cassandra Query Language (CQL).
So thanks to this,
Nhờ đó
you're going to get single-digit millisecond latency
bạn có độ trễ đơn vị millisecond ở mọi quy mô,
at any scale,
và có thể xử lý
and you can do thousands of requests per second.
hàng nghìn request mỗi giây.
Two capacity modes to note, this is just like DynamoDB,
Có hai chế độ capacity giống DynamoDB,
you have the on-demand mode
on-demand
and then you have the provisioned mode with auto-scaling,
và provisioned với auto-scaling,
and these are the same things as DynamoDB really.
hoàn toàn giống DynamoDB.
You get encryption features, backup,
Bạn có tính năng mã hóa, backup,
Point-In-Time Recovery up to 35 days,
Point-In-Time Recovery lên đến 35 ngày,
and so, the use cases is going to be
và use case là
to store IoT device information, time-series data,
lưu thông tin thiết bị IoT, dữ liệu time-series,
and generally, from an exam perspective,
và nhìn chung trong kỳ thi,
anytime you see Apache Cassandra,
cứ thấy Apache Cassandra
you just think about Amazon Keyspaces, and you're done.
thì nghĩ ngay đến Amazon Keyspaces là xong.
Okay, that's it for this short lecture,
Được rồi, hết bài giảng ngắn này,
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.
hy vọng bạn thích và hẹn gặp lại ở bài tiếp theo.